Guide to the Kenneth W. Kennedy World War II Letters
University of Houston Libraries
Kenneth W. Kennedy World War II Letters
1905-1945
1937-1945
2007-019
Kennedy, Kenneth W.
0.50 Linear Feet
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
This collection is primarily concerned with correspondence from Kenneth Wade Kennedy relating to his World War II service. The collection also includes correspondence from various family members, newspaper clippings relevant to the family, and a small number of musicale programs and wedding invitations.
Biographical Information:
Brigadier General Kenneth W. Kennedy was born on September 3, 1918 in Nacogdoches, Texas. He attended Stephen F. Austin University prior to his acceptance to the United States Military Academy at West Point, New York, where he earned a Bachelor of Science in Civil Engineering, Military Engineering, and Military History in 1941. In addition he attended the Army Command and General Staff College in 1944, graduated from the Massachusetts Institute of Technology with a Masters in Civil Engineering in 1947, later attending the Armed Forces Staff College in 1957 and the Army War College in 1962, where he would eventually serve on the faculty as Director of the International Relations Course. General Kennedy’s legacy includes military service in World War II, the Greek Civil War, the Korean War, the Vietnam War and peacetime engineering projects in the United States as well as Japan and Greece. His brother, Joseph W. Kennedy, Ph.D., was instrumental in the discovery of plutonium and noted for his work on the atomic bomb at the Los Alamos laboratory.
During World War II Kennedy served as a shore party commander in the invasion of Northern Africa, receiving a promotion to major for his efforts. Following World War II he served as an engineering advisor to the Greek government during the Greek Civil War, earning commendations from King Paul of Greece. He served as a Base Section Engineer during the Korean War and Senior Engineer Advisor (later named Theater Engineer) during the Vietnam War. In the United States, Kennedy was instrumental in the maintenance of Mississippi River navigation channels, the pioneering construction for early space launch facilities at Cape Canaveral, Florida, and, later, various public works projects and civic service.
During his 30 years of service in the Army Corps of Engineers, Kennedy received a number of accolades and commendations including the Distinguished Service Medal and the Legion of Merit with Cluster. He died at the age of 90 on June 25, 2009 in Lakeway, Texas.
Access Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Genre/Form of Material:
Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence; Invitations; Programs (documents)
Personal Name:
Kennedy, Joseph W. (Joseph William), 1916-1957; Kennedy, Kenneth W.
Topical Term:
World War, 1939-1945
Acquisition Information:
Donated by Tom McKinney January 26, 2009
Conditions Governing Access:
Open for research.
Scope and Contents
This collection is primarily concerned with correspondence from Kenneth Wade Kennedy relating to his World War II service. The collection also includes correspondence from various family members, newspaper clippings relevant to the family, and a small number of musicale programs and wedding invitations.
All letters are arranged chronologically with the exception of a discreet number of letters from various family members which have been arranged alphabetically by author. Newspaper clippings are undated, while programs and wedding invitations have been arranged chronologically.
Detailed List of Contents
- Correspondence from Kenneth W. Kennedy, 1926, 1937-1945, undated
  Scope and Contents
  Letters from Kenneth W. Kennedy are arranged chronologically and include insights into his time spent at West Point and his role in the Northern Africa campaign of World War II.
  - Kenneth W. Kennedy letters, 1926, 1937-1939 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Kenneth W. Kennedy letters, 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Kenneth W. Kennedy letters, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Kenneth W. Kennedy letters, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Kenneth W. Kennedy letters, January 1944-July 1944 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Kenneth W. Kennedy letters, September 1944-August 1945, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence from Kennedy Family, 1942-1944, undated
  Letters from various members of Kenneth W. Kennedy’s family allow for a look into his relations back in the U.S. during World War II. Of particular note are letters from his brother, Joseph Kennedy, sent while working on the discovery of plutonium at the University of California, Berkley and while working on the first atomic bomb at Los Alamos. The fourteenth folder, with letters from various family members, has been arranged chronologically.
  - Maddie Baxter Wade Kennedy, 1942-1944, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Joseph William Kennedy (father), 1942-1944 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Joseph William Kennedy (brother), 1924, 1943-1944, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Adrienne Kennedy, 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Zeno Cox, 1942-1944 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Tissie, 1942-1943, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Joan Williams, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Various family members, 1934-1945, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Newspaper Clippings, undated
  Newspaper clippings are undated and relate primarily to various topics of import to the family, but also include references to Kenneth W. Kennedy and his service during World War II.
  - Various newspaper clippings, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Programs and Invitations, 1905-1912
  A small handful of musicale programs and family wedding invitations are arranged chronologically.
  - Programs, invitations, 1905-1912 (Box 1, Folder 16)